Sean, Kuan-Hsuan Liao



● seankhliao.com☑ sean@liao.dev

Infrastructure / platform engineer with a penchant for programming. I build and maintain the internal platforms for product engineers, and work with them to design and implement features in a cloud native environment. I work with teams to ensure their applications are operationally ready to deliver a fast and reliable experience to our customers

Skills

Platforms: AWS, GCP, Kubernetes, ArgoCD, Istio

Application Delivery: Terraform, Docker, Helm, CircleCI, Github Actions, Jenkins, Ansible

Observability: OpenTelemetry, Prometheus, Datadog, ElasticSearch, PagerDuty, FireHydrant, OpsGenie

Programming: Go (Golang), Shell/Bash, Python

Experience

Infrastructure / Site Reliability Engineer

June 2022 – present London, UK

Snyk

- Technical design and implementation of our Kubernetes cloud re-platforming
- Onboarded incident response vendor for more streamlined incident procedures across the company
- Implemented tooling for SLOs and consulted with teams to raise adoption and reduce alerting fatigue
- Designed and implemented a replatforming of logging (Fluentd/Elastic) and metrics (Prometheus/Grafana) onto Datadog via OpenTelemetry and Vector.
- Maintainer of libraries shared between all Go services
- Worked with open source projects (Dex, OpenTelemetry) to upstream internal improvements
- Additional duties: managing GCP, AWS, K8s, Kyverno, CircleCI, Teleport, Istio, PagerDuty, Postgres/Redis, Backstage

Site Reliability Engineer

March 2022 – June 2022

Deloitte

London, UK

Spearheaded a multi cloud initiative (AWS, GCP) for Deloitte's SaaS product lines.

Infrastructure / Site Reliability Engineer

De Bijenkorf

October 2020-10 – March 2022 Amsterdam, Netherlands

- Standardized and secured Jenkins build pipelines for all services written in JS/TS and Java/Kotlin
- Adopted GitOps with ArgoCD and promoted Continuous Deployment across engineering teams
- Brought the majority of our GCP presence under IaC / terraform.
- Stabilized our logging (Fluentd/Logstash/Elastic) and metrics (Prometheus/Grafana) deployments
- Introduced distributed tracing via auto-instrumentation with OpenTelemetry for Node/JVM services to identify bottlenecks and slowdowns.
- Additional duties: managing GCP, K8s, Postgres/MySQL, OpsGenie, Kafka, and VM deployments with Ansible

Education

MSc, Security and Network Engineering

University of Amsterdam

2019 – 2020 Amsterdam, Netherlands

BBA, Information Management

2014 - 2018

National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

Extracurriculars

Go (programming language)

2019 - present

• I work with the Go project to triage incoming issues, ensuring they are clear, reproducible, and actionable.

seankhliao.com/bloq

• Notes on tech, in public so it may help someone (including the author in the future)